Martin Kaen

Web Developer and FOSS enthusiast living in Buenos Aires

Please visit my **personal website** for links to **LinkedIn** and **Github** at https://mkaen.ar email: mkaen@vivaldi.net | phone: +54 9 351 7703551

I've worked in Digital Communications since 2009. I co-founded a startup in 2015. In 2017 I started to learn web development both with online bootcamps and in-site courses. I'm currently working as a web developer for an IT consulting company. Always learning new skills and digging into Buenos Aires' FOSS ecosystem. Recently started to pursue a 2.5 years technical degree in Software Development.

Work experience

Nov. 2022 ~ now: SSR Software Engineer @ AccionalT [Buenos Aires, Argentina]

Acciona IT is a software consulting company with several regional and international clients. The project that has been assigned to me is the German lab Boehringer Ingelheim where I'm helping to maintain and develop internal company services. #HTML #MySQL #JS #Scrum #Confluence #SmartSimple

Dec. 2020 ~ Nov. 2022: Front-End Dev @ LatinCloud [Buenos Aires, Argentina]

As Front-end developer I worked on the main website and also crafting new products such as a new control panel interface for the company's clients. All these with the support of a solid team of well experienced engineers. #HTML #CSS #JS #PHP #git #NextJS #React #Figma #VueJS #scrum #bash

Feb. 2018 ~ Dec. 2020: Front-End Dev @ Alpogo.com [Buenos Aires, Argentina]

As a start-up founder I had to deal with several topics related to business and product ownership. Since 2018, I begun to code alongside more experienced peers within an agile framework. I had to left the startup in 2020 after a year of covid-19 pandemic hit the industry hard. #HTML #SCSS #JS #PHP #git #codeigniter #MySQL #scrum

Mar. 2009 ~ Dec. 2017: Communications & marketing [Cordoba, Argentina]

Before I shifted my focus to Software Engineering I used to study and work in digital communications (Digital Marketing / Social Media). I studied Communications at Córdoba's University. Since 2010, I started working for an ad-agency (rv.com.ar). Around 2014 I left my position at the agency to work as a freelancer for a year until May 2016 when, alongside a great team, we launched a start-up. #DigitalMedia #BrandStrategy #Trello #scrum

Education

2022~2024: Software Development Technical Degree

In 2022 I started a new career path studying Software Development at a Technical Institute in Buenos Aires. More info about it in my note's repo: github.com/kaenovsky/iftsnotes

2017~2018: Bootcamps (various)

Since 2017 I participated in several online bootcamps on Udemy and two in-site technical courses in web development at the **National Technical University of Buenos Aires**. Find certifications at the bottom of my LinkedIn profile.

2009~2013 [unfinished]: Communications Degree (Córdoba National University, UNC)

At age 17 I moved to Córdoba to study communications. I learned a lot from great classmates and professors, but after some time I decide to work full time at my job back then and I had to drop out school. Some years later I would go back to school, this time to learn how to code.

Languages

Native Spanish. Advanced English (writing & speaking). Basic Chinese (learning with Duolingo for almost a year).

Miscellaneous

I'm a collaborator at the LATAM Free and open source festival **Flisol** where we aim to provide a safe and inclusive environment for people to learn about GNU/Linux. I'm involved with **open source communities** in my city, always looking for ways to improve my skills along side like-minded people.